<ROOT>

<PLACE>Aladdin Tipple</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Other</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 44.638849,-104.162316</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>The Aladdin Tipple in Crook County, Wyoming, was constructed as part of the Aladdin coal mining operations. In 1899, M.S. Kemmerer, who was at the time developing the Kemmerer coalfields, bought the controlling interest in Aladdin mines and the Wyoming and Missouri River Railroad. Kemmerer's purchase of the mines and railroad ensured the venture would have sound financial backing. When coal supply dwindled, the railroad was eventually abandoned. </DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Easy</ACCESS>
<REC>Check it out if you're nearby</REC>
<HAZARDS>Unsafe flooring</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, barbed wire</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Head protection, long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>Alameda Bomb Bunkers</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Other</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 37.793655,-122.325575</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>An old storage facility for nuclear munitions on the Alameda Naval Airstation, former home to the Pacific air wing of the navy. Highly secure bunkers on the far side of the old airfield: Barbed wire, remote controlled vehicle acccess gate, guard towers with gun slots etc.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Easy</ACCESS>
<REC>Worth the trip</REC>
<HAZARDS>None</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, police actively patrolling old NAS</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>None</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>Belleville Mine</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Other (Mine)</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 38.33826,-117.997058</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>A former gold mine with a large mill, conveyor, and various other buildings, machinery, and equipment. The Belleville Mine is in remote Telephone Canyon, seven miles east of Sodaville on the west side of the Pilot Mountains. The mine was first located for gold by Chas. Woodward (also referred to in a different source as Charles Woodruff) in 1927.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Easy</ACCESS>
<REC>Check it out if you're nearby</REC>
<HAZARDS>Rust, unsafe flooring</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>None</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>The Churnel</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Drain</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 38.941153,-104.74009</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>Typical suburban drain with a shrinking outfall/infall. Infall is about a 8x6 box, then downstream at the actual outfall, it is about 12x10 feet with an impressive churn block setup before going into Cottonwood Creek. Two teenagers died here in 2005 during a thunderstorm because they were in the upper portion of the tunnel. They were washed through the system and hit the blocks at its outfall.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Easy</ACCESS>
<REC>Check it out if you're nearby</REC>
<HAZARDS>Flooding, water</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, rocky terrain, police patrol</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Flashlight, rope, gloves, head protection, long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>Gila River Airport</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Other (Outdoors)</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 33.244861,-111.910858</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>The airfield was originally named Goodyear Air Force Auxiliary Airfield when it was constructed sometime around 1943. During World War II, it was renamed Williams Auxiliary Airfield #5, one of the satellites of Williams Air Force base. During that time, it had two 4000 runways and conducted training with twin and 4 engine bombers and single engine fighters. </DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Moderate</ACCESS>
<REC>Worth the trip</REC>
<HAZARDS>None</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, part-time guard, semi-active property</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>None</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>John Marsh House</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Building</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 37.891874,-121.72313</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>The Marsh House was built by John Marsh, the first American settler in the region, and who helped bring settlers to the area. John Marsh bought 17,000 acres in the area, and his lands stretched from the San Joaquin River to the north to the rolling hills in the south, where his ranch resides. Construction on the ranch began in the mid-1850s and was largely built by the Native Americans living in the surrounding areas, whom Marsh was good friends with. Construction was completed in 1856, but Marsh barely furnished the place when he was murdered on September 24, only two weeks after the place was finished.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Difficult</ACCESS>
<REC>Check it out if you're nearby</REC>
<HAZARDS>Rust, unsafe flooring, flooding</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, barbed wire, 24-hour guard, locked gates, wooden boarding</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Flashlight, gloves, long pants/sleeves, permission</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>L.A. Nuclear Escape Tunnels</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Tunnel</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 34.25556,-117.760058</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>Urban legend has it that these two tunnels were built during the cold war in the 1960's in order to provide an alternate escape route for Los Angeles residents in the event of a nuclear attack.  In the 1960s, there was an effort to push through this canyon to the other side but the road itself was never completed.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Easy</ACCESS>
<REC>Check it out if you're nearby</REC>
<HAZARDS>Wild animals, heat exhaustion</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>None</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Flashlight, water</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>Mesa Mill</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Building</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 33.408302,-111.834984</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>There are 2 main levels and then a vertical shaft with a metal ladder that goes up 6 stories to another 2 levels on the very top of the silo's. There is virtually NO graffiti and not much bird crap or trash. There are underground rooms that are accesable via another vertical ladder.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Moderate</ACCESS>
<REC>Check it out if you're nearby</REC>
<HAZARDS>Asbestos, rust, unsafe flooring, water, air quality</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, barbed wire, locked gates, welded doors</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Flashlight, gloves, long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>Murray Coal Processing & Private Scrapyard</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Building</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 40.666892,-111.887991</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>An old coal processing plant with train tracks running on either side of the building. The entire property is covered with old car parts and cars, likely from someone's private stock. Check it out not just for the building, but also for the cars.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Moderate</ACCESS>
<REC>Worth the trip</REC>
<HAZARDS>Asbestos, rust, unsafe flooring</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, barbed wire, dogs, locked gates, wooden boarding</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Gloves, long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>Nevada Abandoned Railroad Yard</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Other (Railroad Yard)</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 35.974017,-114.849583</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>An abandoned railroad yard, formerly owned by Nevada Southern Railway. The site has a lot of different rail cars, some new, others in decay. The older cars are a nice historical site to see if you get a chance.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Easy</ACCESS>
<REC>Worth the trip</REC>
<HAZARDS>Asbestos, rust, unsafe flooring</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, barbed wire</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>Phelps Dodge Mine</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Building</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 33.080285,-109.36244</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>The original location was discovered by an army scout in the late 1800s while he was searching for renegade Apache Indians. In 1935, the main mine, "Clay Pit," was opened by the Detriot Copper Company. The mine itself is an open-pit type, with benches that are anywhere from 100 to 200 feet wide, and 75 feet high.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Difficult</ACCESS>
<REC>Check it out if you're nearby</REC>
<HAZARDS>Rust, flooding, water, air quality, deadly chemicals</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Fences, barbed wire, 24-hour guard, locked gates</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Flashlight, rope, gloves, head protection, steel-toed boots, towelettes, long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>Pueblo Brick Factory</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Building</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 38.210648,-104.667551</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>The site includes many buildings, with one large main factory and several outer buildings, including an office-type building. The office building was a victim of attempted arson and has since been boarded up as a result.</DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Easy</ACCESS>
<REC>Check it out if you're nearby</REC>
<HAZARDS>Asbestos, rust, unsafe flooring, water</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>None</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Flashlight, long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>

<PLACE>The "Slaughterhouse"</PLACE>
<TYPE>Type: Building</TYPE>
<COORDINATES>Coordinates: 37.936726,-121.79614</COORDINATES>
<DESCRIPTION>Known as a "Slaughterhouse" by most people, this is actually a grain mill/feed facility on Empire Mine Road in southern Antioch. It is rumored that there are KKK meetings here and that satanic rituals occur at night. It is also rumored that there is a ghost that roams the grounds at night. </DESCRIPTION>
<ACCESS>Easy</ACCESS>
<REC>Worth the trip</REC>
<HAZARDS>Rust, unsafe flooring, cult members</HAZARDS>
<SECURITY>Part-time guard, locked gates</SECURITY>
<EQUIPMENT>Gloves, long pants/sleeves</EQUIPMENT>



<IMAGES>Locations W/Aladdin/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Aladdin/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Aladdin/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Aladdin/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Alameda/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Alameda/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Alameda/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Alameda/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Belle/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Belle/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Belle/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Belle/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Churnel/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Churnel/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Churnel/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Churnel/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Gila/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Gila/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Gila/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Gila/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/John/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/John/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/John/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/John/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/LA/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/LA/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/LA/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/LA/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Mesa/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Mesa/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Mesa/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Mesa/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Murray/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Murray/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Murray/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Murray/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Nev/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Nev/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Nev/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Nev/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Phelps/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Phelps/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Phelps/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Phelps/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Pueblo/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Pueblo/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Pueblo/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Pueblo/4.jpg</IMAGES>

<IMAGES>Locations W/Sl/1.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Sl/2.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Sl/3.jpg</IMAGES>
<IMAGES>Locations W/Sl/4.jpg</IMAGES>


</ROOT>